Aaron James Banda

Mobile: E-mail: Website: (+63) 918 669-10-76 ajibanda@gmail.com https://ajibanda.github.io/ http://www.ajibanda.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Multi-faceted Software Architect with extensive experience in developing and supporting mission critical applications. A purpose-driven professional active in engaging, training and mentoring others. Bringing an indepth understanding of software deployment and system design illustrated over 11 years of experience in similar roles.

SKILLS

Programming Language C/ C++, Assembly

Scripting Language Ruby, PHP, JavaScript (JQuery), AJAX

Database MySQL, SQLite

Frameworks Rails, Laravel, Codelgniter, Twitter Bootstrap

Server Management UNIX Operating Systems (Ubuntu, CentOS), Cloud, Virtual Private Servers,

Remote Shell Access (SSH), FTP/DNS, WHM, Virtual Box

Others WordPress, Joomla! (CMS), Flash Builder / Flex,

Adobe AIR Applications (AJAX/HTML), PhoneGap, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), HTML, CSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DESIGN ENGINEER

SparkSoft Solutions, Inc. (*Previously Blue Chip Designs, Inc.*) 2008-2019

Job Description: Responsible for planning, designing and full-stack development of projects up to its deployment stage. Also assists lower-level programmers and work closely with clients.

Optical Shop Inventory System (2019)

Designed a system to monitor sales and inventory of a shop with multiple branches.

Front-desk Visitor Login System

Digitized visitors' login system that generates statistics report regarding the visitor flow.

Back-end monitoring for an Internet Provider Client (2017-2018)

Maintains a system designed to monitor multiple servers and other related systems.

Roving Guard Monitoring (2017-2018)

Created a GPS-based system used to track security guards monitoring an area.

Machine Efficiency Monitoring System (2016-2017)

Devised a system for a manufacturing company that to check and monito the efficiency of their equipment by tracking the time of usage and production's output.

Pharmaceutical ERP (2015-2019)

Designed an online system used to track sales from purchasing procedures to delivery to clients. Includes basic accounting procedure to trace clients' payments and printing of invoices and delivery receipts.

SparkSIS (2014-2019)

The predecessor of A-B-SIS; Re-structured the system as it was revised and repackaged to cope with the current K-12 educational system.

Online DBMS for Member Tracking (2013-2019)

Designed a system structure for a multinational company DBMS that is used for tracking and managing its members under their program which includes training schedules and profiling.

SurveyPlus (2013-2014)

Devised a mobile data-collecting system that is generally used for marketing research and surveys via Android devices. This includes a web server for storing and analyzing of data collected.

iSecure-PhilJust (Online Bar Review) (2012-2013)

Created a pay-per view bar review web application for lawyers and students.

i-CALL (Online Language Tutorial) (2011-2012)

Developed an online English tutorial site that handles matching of teachers and students and plotting it in a calendar for scheduling.

Baul (Ballads and Epics Archive) (2010) http://epics.ateneo.edu/epics

Put up an archive site for a Philippine anthropologist's collection. The archive itself stores videos, audio files, photos and articles about the different ballads, epics and traditions of 15 local linguistic groups.

It was redesigned to a PHP based framework (fro ROR) in 2014 due to a client's request.

iGolping (SwingPractis application) (2010) http://vimeo.com/28180393/

Handled the front-end of a *Flex* application for a golf simulation.

VideoVitae (Job Searching Website) (2009)

Worked on a Joomla! based website for online job searching that stores videos as means of application.

A-B-SIS (School Information System) (2008)

Developed an online school information system that allows the schools and universities to manage procedures and other functions even for multiple branches.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Engineering

Pamantasan ng Lungsod ng Maynila (*University of the City of Manila*) Intramuros, Manila; S.Y. 2003–2008

Dean's Lister (2004-2008)

DOST-SEI (R.A. 7687) Scholar (2003-2008)

Department of Science and Technology through Science Education Institute